Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH 002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Albina Delfino Description: Italian-American women and the Communist Party, Needle Trades Industrial Union, National Textile Workers Union; 1930s-40s., Jan 8, 1981 (Cd ohaloh0200092b1p1 / ohaloh0200092b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200093b1p3 / ohaloh0200093b1p4, Cassette 66)
  Transcript available and Index available
- Eugene Dennis Description: with introduction by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, N.D. (Cassette 329)
  no access cassettes available / masters only
- Esther Dolgoff Description: Anarchist women, 1930s., Jan 27, 1982 (Cassette 67, Cd OH-02-025 /OH-02-026, Cd ohaloh020024b1p1 / ohaloh020024b1p2, Cd ohaloh020025b1p3 / ohaloh020025b1p4)
- Bill Dongas Description: Greek publications and radio-Chicago, c. 1940s-1950s., Apr 3, 1983 (Cassette 68)
- Dora Description: Student radicalism, 1930s; Communist Party; United Electrical Workers; social life and friends., Mar 25, 1982 (Cassette 69)
- Pauline Dougherty Description: College politics in depression; union activity and the Left; McCarthy Era., Jan-82 (Cd ohaloh020203b1p1 / ohaloh020203b1p2 / ohaloh020204b1p3, Cd ohaloh020204b1p4 / ohaloh020205b1p5 /ohaloh020205b1p6, Cd ohaloh020206b1p7, Cassette 70)
- Susan Drake-Raphals Description: Workers Party; C.L.R. James; 1940s., May 7, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020207b1p1 /ohaloh020207b1p2, Cd ohaloh020208b1p3 / ohaloh020208b1p4, Cassette 71)
- Hal Draper Description: Editor of Labor Action, 1949-1958; problems of "Shachtmanite" group., Nov 5, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020209b1p1 / ohaloh020209b1p2, Cd ohaloh020210b1p3 / ohaloh020210b1p4, Cassette 72)
  Electronic transcript available
- Walter Duda Description: Lithuanian-American Left activities, 1920s-50s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 73, Cd ohaloh020211p1 / ohaloh020211p2)
- Jane Dudley Description: Dance and left politics; New Dance group; Martha Graham; civil rights., 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-139, Cassette 74, Cd ohaloh0200139p1)
  Transcript available, Box 1 and Index available
- Raya Dunayevskaya Description: Trotskyism, 1930s; Johnson- Forest group, 1940s; coal strikes of 1949-50 and News and Letters organization., Mar 24, 1983 (Cassette 75)
- George Edwards Description: Garveyite, 1920s; semiprofessional football player, prohibition-era gangster, Kansas-Nebraska district, 1930s-40s., Nov 4, 1983 (Cassette 76A-C)
  Transcript availalbe, Box 1 and index available
- Herb Edwards Description: Wisconsin lumber, Industrial Workers of the World; Elmer Smith; San Quentin., Feb 12, 1972 (Item Transcript only)
- Hoddee Edwards Description: Boston Jewish community; Communist activist in California; People's World, 1949; life in Ghana; c. 1920s-60s., Nov 12, 1983 (Cassette 78A-B)
- Melech Epstein Description: Editorship of Freiheit and Yiddish publications; Israel and 1970s American politics., Jan 9, 1974 (Cassette 79)
- Virginia Epstein Description: Socialist Party; Communist Party; American Council on US-Soviet Friendship; Committee of American Women; c. 1910-1920s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 80, Cd Access OH-02-027 / OH-02-028, Cd ohaloh020026b1p1 / ohaloh020026b1p2, Cd ohaloh020027b1p3 / ohaloh020027b1p4)
- Ernest Erber, March 23, 1984 (Cassette 365A-B)
- S. Evelyn Description: Young Communist League; anti-Nazi and pro-Republican Spain; 1930s., Jun 25, 1982 (Cassette no tape)
- Seymour Faber Description: Radical Zionism; Johnson-Forest Tendency; Detroit 1930s-60s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 82A-B)
- Elmer Felhaber Description: Minnesota newspaper unionism; CIO and Communist Party; Ohio Left after WWII; c. 1930s-1950s., 2/5/1981 (Cassette 83A-B)
- Duncan Ferguson Description: (Memorial Meeting) Eulogy by Harry Ring, of sculptor and activist in Socialist Workers Party, 1940s-70s., 1975 (Cassette 84)
- Lawrence Ferlinghetti Description: Beat Generation; San Francisco avant-garde arts and anarchism; formation of City Lights bookstore and publishing company; 1940s-early 1950s., Dec-81 (Cd ohaloh020088p1 / ohaloh020088p2, Cd Access OH-02-093 / OH-02-094, Cassette 85)
  Electronic transcript available and Index available
- Joseph Figueredo Description: Portuguese-American Left; absence of Portuguese- language Communist press; use of local radio; activities in ILWU, c. 1920s-1970s., Nov 3, 1983 (Cassette 86, Cd ohaloh020212b1p1 / ohaloh020212b1p2 / ohaloh020213b1p3, Cd ohaloh020213b1p4 / ohaloh020214b1p5 / ohaloh020214b1p6, Cd ohaloh020215b1p7 / ohaloh020215b1p8)
- Bruno Fisher, Nov. 1982 (Cassette 308C)
- Morris Fisher Description: Labor Zionism and Workmen's Circle; Jewish Socialist Farband, Miami Beach Yiddishkayt; c. 1930s-1970s., Mar 16, 1983 (Cassette 87, Cd ohaloh020216p1 / ohaloh020216p2)
- Jacob Fisherman, Nov 3, 1979 (Cassette 393)
- Henry Foner Description: Teacher's union activities; Communist Party and Ben Gold;, 1948-1970s., Mar 29, 1976 (Item Transcript only)
- Emmanuel Fried, 1977-1983 (Cassette 310A (May 1980) / 310B (Oct 30, 1980) / 310C (March 1980), Cassette 310D (June 8, 1977) / 310E June 1978))
- William (bill) Friedland Description: Workers Party; music and creation of record, Songs for Sectarians., May 6, 1983 (Cassette 89, Cd ohaloh020217p1 / ohaloh020217p2)
- Isadore Friedland & Max Fishgol d Description: Union activities and the Left, 1930s- 1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 90, Cd ohaloh020218p1 / ohaloh020218p2)
- Mary Gale Description: ILGWU; Scottsboro case, American Labor Party; c.1920s-1930s., Jan 29, 1982 (Cassette 91, Cd ohaloh020219b1p1 / ohaloh020219b1p2, Cd ohaloh020220b1p3 / ohaloh020220b1p4, Cd ohaloh020221b1p5 / ohaloh020221b1p6)
- Alex & Faye Gardners; Abe & Hodes Kantor Description: Unemployed councils; Workers' Club; WPA; Garibaldi Clubs; Marcantonio, union activities; c1930s-1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 93, Cd ohaloh020224b1p1 / ohaloh020224b1p2, Cd ohaloh020225b1p3 / ohaloh020225b1p4)
- Sender Garlin Description: Socialist Party; working at the Daily Worker, 1920s-30s., Oct 14, 1976 (Cassette 92, Cd ohaloh020222b1p1 / ohaloh020222b1p2, Cd ohaloh020223b1p3 / ohaloh020223b1p4)
- Hugo Gellert Description: Cartoonist and graphic artist with work in Masses magazine, New Yorker, New York newspapers,and Hungarian-American Left newspaper, Uj Elore; 1930s, Apr 4, 1984 (Cd Access Oh-02-030 / OH-02-031, Cd ohaloh020029b1p1 / ohaloh029b1p2, Cd ohaloh020030b1p3, Cassette 94)
- Sophie Melvin Gerson Description: Young Communist League; Passaic and Gastonia textile strikes; 1920s., Mar 26, 1976 (Item Transcript only)
- Joseph Giganti Description: Italian-American Communist newspaper, Il Lavoratore; "Oehlerite" faction of Trotskyists, and their Chicago activity, 1920-1930s., Jul 26, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020226b1p1 / ohaloh020226b1p2, Cd ohaloh020227b1p3 / ohaloh020227b1p4, Cassette 96)
- Todd Gitlin Description: Students for a Democratic Society, 1960, Mar 1, 1970 (Cassette 97)
- Barbara Gittings Description: Gay liberation movement, 1950s-70s, Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 98A-C)
  no access cassette for 98C / master only
- Jessie Glaberma n Description: Socialist Workers Party and Workers Party in New York, Philadelphia and Detroit, 1930s-1950s., Aug 17, 1977-Sep 3, 1977 (Cassette 99A-G)
- Martin Glaberman Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency; New York and Detroit, 1940s-50s., Mar 29, 1983 (Cassette 100)
- Ruth Glassman Description: American Youth Congress; WWII and shop agitation; United Electrical Workers; 1930s., Feb 1, 1979 (Cd ohaloh020228b1p1 / ohaloh020228b1p2, Cd ohaloh020229b1p3 / ohaloh020229b1p4, Cassette 101)
- Kaya Gliden, Nov. 21, 1976 (Cassette 309A)
- Albert Glotzer Description: Communist Party; American Trotskyism; Workers Party; c. 1920s-1940s., Dec 13, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020230b1p1 / ohaloh020230b1p2 / ohaloh020231b1p3, Cd ohaloh020231b1p4 / ohaloh020232b1p5 / ohaloh020232b1p6, Cd ohaloh020233b1p7 / ohaloh020233b1p8, Cassette 102)
- Albert Glotzer, Oct 24, 1973 (Cassette 335A-B)
- Lillian Gold Description: Socialist Party, War Resisters' League, FDR & trade unions., Apr 4, 1982 (Cassette 103, Cd Access OH-02-032 / OH-02-033, Cd ohaloh020031b1p1 / ohaloh020031b1p2, Cd ohaloh020032b1p3 / ohaloh020032b1p4)
- Itche Goldberg Description: Immigration and Canadian Yiddish background; Left Yiddishkayt in New York, 1920s-30s; struggle for autonomy wihin Communist framework; Yiddish pedagogy versus politics; reflections., Jun 5, 1982 (Cassette Access OH-02-034, Cassette 104, Cassette ohaloh020033)
- Itche Goldberg Description: Jewish cultural movement.., Feb 17, 1983 (Cassette 105, Cd ohaloh020034p1 / ohaloh020034p2, Cd Access OH-02-035)
- K. Golden, Nov. 21, 1976 (Cassette 366A-B)
- Mollie Goldstein Description: Communist Party; women's organizations; price and rent protests in Brooklyn and the Bronx; 1930s., Nov 7, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-036 / OH-02-037, Cassette 106, Cd ohaloh020035b1p1 / ohaloh020035b1p2, Cd ohaloh020036b1p3)
- Nina Goldstein Description: Communist Party, Freiheit, International Workers Order; Russian War Relief and aid to Israel, c. 1920s-1940s., Mar 19, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020234b1p1 /ohaloh020234b1p2, Cassette 107)
- Walter Goldwater Description: C.L.R. James; Workers Party; Trotskyism, anti-Stalinism, neo-conservatism, Pan-Africanism; 1930s-1960s., Feb 15, 1983 (Cassette 108A-B)
  no access cassette for 108B / master only
- Goolhman, N.D. (Cassette 394)
  no access cassette available / master only
- Helen Goodman, n.d.
- Michael Gordon Description: Frontier Films, Film and Photo League, 1930s., Mar 25, 1977 (Cassette 109)
- Grandma was an Activist Description: Radio series on women radicals of 1930s, in six half-hour parts, produced from OHAL interviews for WBAI-FM; includes excerpts from interviews with Louise Thompson, Jane Dudley, Alice Dodge Wolfson, Meridel LeSueur et. al., 1983 (Cassette 110A-C)
- Leah-Dillon Grant Description: Yiddish literary milieu; Johnson-Forest Tendency; c. 1920s-1940., Jul 24, 1983 (Cassette 111)
- Samuel Greenberg Description: Yiddish culture and the Left; Los Angeles Yiddish Left from the 1930s-present., Oct 27, 1982 (Cassette 112A-B)
- Sam Grober, Nov. 5, 1979 (Cassette 395)
- Sarah Gudelman, Nov. 3, 1979 (Cassette 396A-B)
- National Guardian Forum Description: New Communist Party; criticism of 1960s' politics., May 26, 1905 (Cassette 113)
- Oive Halonen Description: Finnish-American radicalism; participation in Spanish Civil War as member of Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Seattle machinist, 1940s-60s., Feb 27, 1978 (Cassette 114)
- Michael Hanusiak Description: Ukrainian-American Left; International Workers Order; effect of McCarthyism; 1930s-1940s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 115)
- Louis Harap Description: Harvard University, 1930s; Jewish Survey, 1940s; Rosenberg case; Jewish Currents 1950s-70s., Mar 19, 1978 (Cassette 116A-B)
  Transcript and index available
- Harlem Riots Inquiry, March 14, 1965 (Cassette 386)
- Michael Harrington Description: "Prehistory" of Students for a Democratic Society., Oct 6, 1969 (Cd ohaloh020236p1 /ohaloh020236p2, Cassette 117)
- Michael Harrington, May 2, 1988 (Cassette 117.5, Cd ohaloh020237b1p1 / ohaloh020237b1p2, Cd ohaloh020238b1p3 / ohaloh020238b1p4, Cd ohaloh020239b1p5 / ohaloh020239b1p6)
- Daniel Hartquist Description: Socialist movement in Sweden and Swedish- American Socialism; Left in New England., Feb 5, 1981 (Cassette 118, Cd ohaloh020240b1p1 / ohaloh020240b1p2, Cd ohaloh020241b1p3 /ohaloh020241b1p4)
  Transcript available, box 1 and index available
- James B. Henry Description: Legal prosecution of the International Workers Order in New York State, 1950s. Ex-Special Assistant Attorney General, May 11, 1976 (Cassette 119A-B)
- Michael Henry, June 6, 1980 (Cassette 119, Cd ohaloh020242b1p1 / ohaloh020242b1p2, Cd ohaloh020243b1p3 / ohaloh020243b1p4)
- Otis Hood Description: Union background; New England Left and communism, in 1930s., Mar 25, 1981 (Cassette 120A-B)
- Walter Hoopes Description: St. Louis Free Thought; Rand School; Socialist Party; 1940s-1970s., Oct 6, 1984 (Cassette 121A-B)
- Frank Horzen Description: Fontana, California; (anti-socialist) South Slav benefit association; attitude toward Henry Kaiser., Oct 26, 1982 (Cassette 122, Cd ohaloh020037p1 /ohaloh020037p2, Cd access OH-02-038)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers Union Description: 11 anonymous women and men, 1910-30s., 1974-1977 (Cassette 123A-K)
- International Labor Defense Description: David Freeman, Sam Neuberger, and Fay Pasternak on ILD, National Lawyers Guild and radical legal work; recollections of Joe Brodsky, Carol King, Vito Marcantonio, and others; 1930s-1940s., Jun 12, 1982 (Cassette 124A-C)
- Evelyn Irsay, June 1982 (Cassette 383)
- S.J Jakubka Description: Editorship of Vilnis, Chicago Lithuanian-language newspaper; ethnic newspaper; Lituanian-American movement; 1940s., Jul 28, 1983 (Cassette 125A-C)
- CLR James, Feb. 25, 1971 (Cassette 361)
- CLR James, Oct. 15, 1981 (Cassette 369)
- Jewish People's Chorus Description: Excerpt from performance at Yablon Center, Los Angeles., Apr 14, 1980 (Cassette 126)
- Howard Johnson Description: Harlem show business in 1930s; Cotton Club; Jackie Robinson, Paul Robeson; Sound reel from his night class., Oct 17, 1979 (Cd access OH-02-039, Cd ohaloh020038p1 / ohaloh020038p2, Cassette 127)
- Ohni Kaartinen Description: Finnish-American radical background; Spanish Civil war; 1930s-1970s., Jul 7, 1984 (Cassette 128A-B)
- Morris Kaplan Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish cultural movement, Jul 15, 1984 (Cassette 129)
- Maude White Katz Description: COmmunist Party; Needle Trades Industrial Union, 1920s., Oct 18, 1981 (Cd ohaloh0200140p1, Cd Access OH-02-140, Cassette 130)
- Ed Kempf Description: Steel Workers Organizing Committee-Harrison-Hoboken- Jersey City, Crucible Steel-Otis Elevator, Socialist Party and Socialist Workers Party, 1930s., Oct 29, 1978 (Cassette 131)
- Aaron Kertmann Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 7, 1980 (Cassette 132)
- Anton Kerzic Description: Slovenian-American fraternal movement; Finnish-American fraternal group in milk co-op,; founder of savings and loan bank; 1930s-1950s., Jul 27, 1983 (Cassette 133A-B)
- Maurice Kish Description: Brief interview with Russian-born painter about his family and his work., Feb 17, 1983 (Cassette 134)
- Maurice Kish, Sept. 23, 1979 (Cassette 397A-B)
- Maurice Kish, Oct. 29, 1979 (Cassette 398)
- Camp Kinderland Reunion Description: Reminiscences; reading of letters; songs and dances., Jun 9, 1979 (Cassette 135A-B)
- Mary Kolehmainen Description: Finnish-American Left;editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri., Mar 10, 1981 (Cassette 136-137)
- Joseph Korn Description: YKUF, L.A. Jewish Cultural Movement, Apr 16, 1983 (Cassette 138)
- Ernest Koski Description: Finnish-American Left in Mesabi Iron Range; Tyomies newspaper., Jul 31, 1983 (Cassette 139A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 139B / master only
- Nettie Kravitz Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency, radical feminism, ,1940s-60s, Apr 1, 1983 (Cassette 140A-B)
- Rose Kryzak Description: Communist Paerty and women, McCarthy period., Jan 4, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-040, Cassette 141, Cd ohaloh020039p1 / ohaloh020039p2)
- Jacob Kunin Description: Ethnic groups and politics, Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1920s-40s., Mar 2, 1967 (Cassette transcript only)
- Kay Lahusen Description: Gay liberation movement; legislative and political campaigns; c. 1950s-1970s., Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 143A-B)
  No Access Cassette 143B / master only
- Ollie Leeds, Aug. 9, 1983 (Cassette 370A-C)
- Mieridel LeSueur Description: Minnesota depression, radicalism, 1930s., May 1, 1982 (Cassette 144)
- Aaron Levenstein, March 5, 1974 (Cassette 336)
- Alfred Baker Lewis Description: Socialist Party; civil rights movement; c.1940s-60s., Sep 8, 1967 (Cassette Transcript Only)
- Fred Lilja Description: Work as miner, lumber worker and fisherman; activities of Finnish-American Left; 1920s-1950., Jun 28, 1983 (Cassette 146)
- N. Lillian Description: Brooklyn College, National Students' League, Medical Bureau of Aid to Spanish Democracy; 1930s., May 19, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-041, Cassette 147, Cd ohaloh020040p1 / ohaloh020040p2)
- Sam Liptzin, Mar. 22, 1979 (Cassette 399)
- Frank Lovell, Jan. 19, 1990 (Cassette 312A-B)
- Frank Lovell, Feb. 2, 1990 (Carton 313)
- Luisa Description: United Electrical Workers Local 431, Emerson Electric Co., Jersey City., May 19, 1982 (Cassette 148A-B)
- James Lustig Description: Hungarian-American Left; fur-leather and electrical workers; Henry Wallace's farm; work on Uj Elore and Hungarian-American Word,; 1920s-1970s., Oct 20, 1982 (Cassette 149)
  No Access Cassette / Master only
- A.B. Magil Description: Yiddish culture; Daily Worker, 1920s., Oct 31, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-042 / OH-02-043, Cassette 150, Cd ohaloh020041b1p1 / ohaloh020041b1p2, Cd ohaloh020042b1p3)
- A.B. Magil, Jan. 5, 1994 (Cassette 332A-D)
- Vito Magil Description: Youth leader of Vito Marcantonio movement; editor of Communist Italian-language paper, L'Unita., May 15, 1983 (Cassette 151, Cd ohaloh020043b1p1 / ohaloh020043b1p2, Cd ohaloh020044b1p3, Cd Access OH-02-044 / OH-02-045)
  No Access Cassettes / Masters only
- Mary Magner Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party, executive secretary of Socialist Mayor Jasper McLevy, 1940-1957., Jan 26, 1975 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Robin Maisel Description: Socialist Workers Party; experience in print shops., May 4, 1975 (Cassette 153A-C)
- Julius Manford a.k.a. Morty Description: Gay rights, Aug 6, 1983 (Cassette 154A-C)
- Emmanuel Maravchik, Dec. 6, 1973 (Cassette 337)
- Julius Margolin, Description: Food Workers Industrial Union; National Maritime Union; WW II no-strike pledge; Communist view of Trotskyism; 1930s-50s., Dec 30, 1983 (Cassette 155)
- Alice Marsh Description: Socialist Party, 1930s; the struggle between Communists and Socialists in the Teachers Union., Feb 24, 1982 (Cassette 156)
- Anthony Martocchia and Philip Lamantia Description: Anarchist origins in Italy and his anti-fascist activities in Chicago; San Francisco/Las Gatos anarchist group; Philip Lamantia; importance of Malatesta; c.1920-1950., Oct 31, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-046, Cassette 157, Cd ohaloh020045b1p1 / ohaloh020045b1p2, Cd ohaloh020046b1p3)
- Matteotti Club Description: Reunion of Rhode Island activists in Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Campaign, 50 years after execution., 1977 (Cassette 158A-B)
- David Mattis, Dec, 28, 1979 (Cassette 400)
- Grace McDonald (Burnham), Aug. 25, 1973 (Cassette 360)
- Tom McGrath Description: Literature in the 1930s; poetry and the Popular Front; Cold War and Left Culture., Mar 9, 1977 (Cassette 168)
- Tom McGrath Description: Remeberance of the Chelsea Cornodes, N.D. (Cassette 345)
- Ernest Rice McKinney Description: Activities as Socialist and Communist, "Musteite", and "Shachtmanite" (1940s); Unemployed Leagues, A. Philip Randolph; c. 1920s-1940s., Feb 25, 1983 (Cassette 169)
- Vida McLevy Description: Socialist Party, career of her husband Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, 1933-1957., Nov 4, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Medem Jewish Socialist Group/Forum on Jews and the Left Description: Discussion by Paul Buhle and Arthur Liebman of Jews and the Left in the US, 1890- present, with questions from audience and response., Feb 26, 1982 (Cassette 159A-B)
- Sophie Melvin-Gerson Description: Russian background; imprisonment due to strike., Mar 13, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Claire Michelson Description: department store and labor related strikes., Oct 29, 1979 (Cd Access OH-02-047 / OH-02-048, Cassette 164, Cd ohaloh020047p1 / ohaloh020047p2)
  Transcript Available, Box 1 and Index available
- Nick Migas Description: Unionism and politics in Gary, Indiana, 1930s-40s; Wisconsin National Farmers Union, 1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 160)
- Eva Mizara Description: Lithuanian-American radicalism 1920s-1960s, Jun 24, 1983 (Cassette 162)
- Mother Audley Moore Description: Youth in New Orleans; Marcus Garvey movement; Communist Party in Harlem; 1920s-1930s, 1972 (Cd ohaloh020048b1p1 / ohaloh020048b1p1, Cd ohaloh020049b1p2 / ohaloh020049b1p4, Cassette 163, Cd Access OH-02-049 / OH-02-050)
  Transcript available, Box 2
- Mother Audley Moore Description: Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s, Dec 23, 1981 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Anna Morgan Description: Depression, Communist Party; 1930s-50s., Jan 22, 1981-Jan 29, 1981 (Cassette 165A-D)
- Gussie Moskowitz Description: Hungarian-American, Furriers Union, Communist Party, Jun 4, 1976 (Cd Access OH-02-051, Cd ohaloh020050p1 / ohaloh020050p2, Cassette 166)
- Elma Munckton Description: Life in U.S. for domestic workers; Finnish-American Left, 1920s-60s., Nov 9, 1983 (Cassette 167)
  Transcript available, Box 2 and index available
- Jim Murray, June 6, 1984 (Cassette 346)
- Rosemarie. B. Haskell Muscat, Apr 13, 1980 (Cassette 170A-B)
- John MItchell Description: Packinghouse Workers, Communist Party, 1940s-50s., Mar 30, 1981 (Cassette 161A-B)
- Morris Nadelman Description: Yiddish Anarchist origins and activities; Rudolf Rocker; activities in Arbeter Ring; Spanish Civil war., Apr 8, 1980 (Cassette 171A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 171A / Master Only
- Al Nash, Dec. 8, 1983 (Cassette 347)
- Luigi Nardella Description: Speech delivered to Rhode Island Labor History Forum, unemployed movement in R.I., 1930s., Mar-78 (Cassette 172A-C)
- Steve Nelson Description: Chicago unemployed activities; activities in anthracite coal districts; Popular Front and Spanish Civil War., 1981 (Cd ohaloh020051p1 / ohaloh020051p2, Cd ohaloh020052p1 / ohaloh020052p2, Cassette 173, Cd Aceess OH-02-052 / OH-02-053, Cd Access OH-54 / OH-02-055)
  Electronix transcript available and Index available
- Esta Nette Description: one 1978 interview and one DVD interview; history of the Pioneers; Young Communist League and protests. (Cd OH-02-388 / OH-02-389)
- Rose Nobel, Feb. 28, 1981 (Cassette 385A-B)
- Joseph Norrick and Ruth Norrick Description: Indiana coal mining traditions; "Americanizing" Communism; Ruth Norrick, Eugene Debs; Cold War and UN Children' agency; c. 1930s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cd ohal02020054b1p3 / ohaloh020054b4, Cd ohaloh020055b1p5 / ohaloh020055b1p6, Cassette 174, Cd Access OH-02-056 to OH-02-057)
- Clarence Norris Description: "Scottsboro Boys" case recalled by one of nine defendents, roles of Inter-national Labor Defense and NAACP; and circumstances of his pardon., Feb 25, 1981 (Cassette 175)
- Paul Novick, c. 1979 (Cassette 401)
- Paul Novick, Nov. 3, 1981 (Cassette 347)
- Paul Novick Description: Yiddish culture; employment by the Groysser Kundes magazine; move to Morgen Freiheit., Jan 20, 1983 (Cassette 176)
- Paul Novick, Feb. 9, 1985 (Cassette 402)
  no access available / master only
- Stanley Nowack Description: Polish-American Left; cigar workers; UAW; American Slav Congress; Polish-American Left organizations, 1910s- 1930s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 177A-C)
- Marjorie O'Brien Description: University of Wisconsin Trotskyist circle; C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency., May 7, 1983 (Cassette 178)
- Harvey O'Connor Description: Seattle during 1919 general strike; Federated Press, House Un-American Activities Committee, c.1920s-1950s., Sep 27, 1977 (Cd ohaloh020056b1p1 / ohaloh020056b1p2, Cd ohaloh020057b1p3 / ohaloh020057b1p4, Cd ohaloh020058b1p5, Cassette 180, Cd Access OH-02-058 to OH-02-060)
- Edna Ocko Description: The Left and dance; form and content in radicalism and modern dance., 1981 (Cassette 181)
- Margaret O'Hara, April 22, 1980 (Cassette 371)
  No access cassette available / master only
- Gene O'Hare (Cassette 182A-B)
- Bertell Ollman Description: Madison Students League for Industrial Democracy, Students for Democratic Action., Nov 5, 1982 (Cassette 349-350)
- Celia Orlansky, Oct. 27, 1981 (Cassette 351-352)
- Myra Page Description: Southern writer and novelist; authored: The Gathering Storm and Moscow Yankee, 1930s., 1982 (Cassette 183A-B)
- John Pandera Description: Left in South Slav sections of San Pedro 1930s-1950s, Oct 22, 1982 (Cassette 184)
- Morris Pasternak, March 21, 1978 (Cassette 381)